Nikhil: Well, hello.
Kostadis Roussos: Hello?
Kostadis Roussos: Can you hear me?
Nikhil: I can hear you.
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent, excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: Just… Sitting.
Kostadis Roussos: How about now? Can you hear me now?
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: Excellent, excellent, excellent, excellent.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, now let me go through this.
Nikhil: You got any long weekend plans?
Kostadis Roussos: No, not really.
Kostadis Roussos: I was gonna have long weekend plans, but my, dog… anyway, my dog, his stuff, I had to go get…
Kostadis Roussos: Spade, so… We're not.
Nikhil: What about your dog?
Kostadis Roussos: Spade. It's, when dogs get, it's when you snip a dog.
Nikhil: Oh, right, right, okay, okay.
Nikhil: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: Nice.
Kostadis Roussos: Suck.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: So, hold on, while I'm…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, Phandelver, that's what I'm looking for.
Kostadis Roussos: So there's a… so I'm… I'm dyslexic, right? So…
Kostadis Roussos: there's, like, times when I cannot spell things to save my life.
Nikhil: Is it… is it that? That's how it works.
Kostadis Roussos: It works in a variety of ways, but for me, that's how it works.
Nikhil: When I was a kid, I used to get confused between on and no, those two words, you know?
Kostadis Roussos: I am not an expert in the area.
Kostadis Roussos: I agree.
Nikhil: So I thought I…
Kostadis Roussos: I actually went and got myself tested, because I'm not an expert in the area.
Nikhil: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, I can't find the relevant music for this today, so we'll just have to deal with this.
Kostadis Roussos: not have relevant music. Okay, let me see if we… hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: At least have…
Kostadis Roussos: There isn't one.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, not for today's scene.
Kostadis Roussos: How dare they?
Kostadis Roussos: They set you up, and then they tear you down, that's all I have to say.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, okay. So, just to remind you of what was going on…
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just, I sent you that, Quick summary.
Kostadis Roussos: You've just met with, Hamun Kost.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? The, Red Wizard of Thay.
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: necromancer, who said he knew where the cave Wave Echo Cave was.
Nikhil: No, sorry, not the…
Kostadis Roussos: Cragmaw Castle.
Kostadis Roussos: Which is your next, hint as to where,
Kostadis Roussos: what's his name? Gundren… Gundren…
Nikhil: Roxy.
Kostadis Roussos: Glass… Gundren Rockseeker is Iarno Glasstaff, and, your,
Kostadis Roussos: And what's his name? The Spider.
Nikhil: Spider, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You, you had two quests, one, you had one quest, which was to go deal with,
Kostadis Roussos: Actually, 3 quests. You had 2 quests. You had a quest to go deal with some raiders.
Kostadis Roussos: A quest to deal with,
Kostadis Roussos: a… Bonsai, and now… and then you decided that neither of those quests were cool enough, so you decided to go and get a third quest.
Nikhil: No, I think, he had a quest at Wyvern Tor.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, yeah, he had a third… his was the third quest.
Nikhil: Correct, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: So there's… Or was it the same cost? Anyway, so here we are.
Kostadis Roussos: So,
Kostadis Roussos: You kind of arrived… you've arrived at this, this, this location. Let me just get the description up.
Kostadis Roussos: No, actually, it is true. The Wyvern Tor is the same one. Yes, you are correct.
Nikhil: Yes, yes, yeah. My mistake. Yeah, I chose Wyvern Tor.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he chose one… okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, sorry. The faint smell of smoke hangs in the air as you ascend a rugged ridge down the lower slopes of the hill. 50 yards away, a cave mouth opens up at the bottom of a ravine, hunkered down by a boulder 20 yards outside the cave. Evidently keeping watch is a single budbearer.
Nikhil: That's what I see now.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, what do you want to do?
Nikhil: Hmm… So we are here.
Nikhil: Do I have the range to shoot a… Idle?
Kostadis Roussos: You definitely have the range to shoot the arrow. The question on the table is… you know…
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, you do. You definitely have the range to shoot.
Nikhil: Oh, it's 80… It is the range, I think.
Nikhil: Okay.
Nikhil: So we can see only one bugbear, standing over there.
Kostadis Roussos: In front of a cave mouth, right?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah, okay.
Nikhil: Mmm… I would want…
Kostadis Roussos: You can ask your allies what they think you should do.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: They are there, and they do that.
Nikhil: Yeah, I'm gonna head back and start a discussion.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty.
Nikhil: Okay, guys, so I see a bugbear…
Nikhil: At the far end of the cave.
Nikhil: Yeah, ravine.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, a ravine. Yeah, that's…
Nikhil: At the ravine? Okay, yeah, yeah. So, I was thinking I could use my shortbow and, take that guy out.
Nikhil: But he's kind of far, and I think I'll be able to make it. What do you…
Nikhil: guys want to do? Do you have any better idea to tackle the situation?
Kostadis Roussos: sweet.
Kostadis Roussos: Well…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, I mean, so Pip says, well, the first thing we should do is
Kostadis Roussos: Check to see if he's doing anything.
Nikhil: What do you mean is doing anything?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, is he the kind of guard that sends his time thinking hard, or is he the kind of guard that, you know, is, what kind of guard is here?
Nikhil: Well…
Nikhil: To explore that, you need to go close to him, and I think it's a bad idea going close to him.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you could get somewhat close to him, right? I mean.
Nikhil: You, you…
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at you, you can sneak, right?
Nikhil: I can sneak, but, well, yeah, yeah, I guess you're right, okay, I can…
Nikhil: can go as close as possible. Let me try.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: So I'll do a sneak phone.
Nikhil: Stealth.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Nikhil: So, 25.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You, get close enough to be able to see him.
Nikhil: Okay.
Nikhil: Mmm…
Kostadis Roussos: He's got one eye, which is a milky film.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? So he's basically blind in one eye, and he leans on a salvaged pike.
Nikhil: Salvaged bike?
Kostadis Roussos: Pike. Pike. P-I-K-E-E.
Nikhil: Pike…
Kostadis Roussos: Do you know what that is? If you don't, it's a wep… it's a weapon. It's a… it's a long, punky weapon. It's like a polearm.
Nikhil: I think so. Let me see… Oh, okay.
Nikhil: Like a spear.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Great.
Kostadis Roussos: So he's got this… he's gotta, kind of, like, sitting there, guarding… guarding.
Nikhil: Do I see anyone else?
Kostadis Roussos: Try to see… you want to try to see inside?
Kostadis Roussos: What you do notice about him… what you do notice about him is that he's kind of bored.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, he feels like, you know, he's got that look of somebody who,
Kostadis Roussos: Really doesn't want to be doing this.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you're gonna try to see what else you can notice?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you can't see into the cave, it's too dark.
Nikhil: Correct.
Kostadis Roussos: But… You can, definitely smell the Cook Fire smoke.
Nikhil: From inside the cave?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: So, there's definitely somebody else inside there.
Kostadis Roussos: And so…
Nikhil: Can I use the mage hand and, you know, try to do some magic kind of thing, like…
Nikhil: You know, throw off his bike, or, you know.
Nikhil: Throw a stone at him, something like that, without being noticed.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see…
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, you could… oh, I mean, you could use it to throw it from a different location, for example. Like, you could move your mage hand…
Kostadis Roussos: You could place your mage hand 30 feet away, right? So you could put it, like, over here.
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And, have it… have it go there.
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah, that's what I mean.
Kostadis Roussos: All right, so that's a great plan. What do you want to do with the rest of your party? They're, like, 60 feet away.
Kostadis Roussos: Very far away, so they're, like, at least more than one round away from coming here.
Nikhil: So, I want to get them here,
Kostadis Roussos: Get them where I put, place them.
Nikhil: Boom.
Kostadis Roussos: Click where you want them.
Nikhil: Here.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Nikhil: Like, I guess they are not seen if they are here.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you want to, let's say, roll their stealth. Once they're… let me just see what their passive… there's the passive.
Nikhil: Stealth for food?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, hold on, hold on, hold on, just do it, let me just… let me just save myself some time.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, this guy's got some pretty strong stealth, so,
Kostadis Roussos: If they… and that's something that, so do you… do you… okay, so you're gonna try to do that, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, roll… roll… roll a group… well, we have to roll a group passive… a stealth check, so roll 3D6.
Kostadis Roussos: That's right. Roll… let's roll 3D20 for all of the characters and see what they do, so… Alright.
Nikhil: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, unfortunately… He notices something, so he steps over here.
Kostadis Roussos: what do you want to do? He doesn't know what he's noticed, but he's noticed something.
Nikhil: So, I still want to use my mage hand, from the other side to distract him from the north.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you're gonna use your mage hand to distract him?
Kostadis Roussos: How do you distract… how do you distract him?
Nikhil: So, behind him, assuming he's facing south.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep, he's facing south, yep.
Nikhil: Alright, so he should hear rocks roll down, or, you know, maybe a stone hitting the wall.
Nikhil: Okay. Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so he's hitting a wall. Okay, so once he does that, what do you want to do?
Nikhil: So he's gonna turn around, and then maybe, you know.
Nikhil: do that again from the east and the west, so… he kind of…
Nikhil: thinks that there's someone, and I want him to call for help.
Kostadis Roussos: So you want everybody to come out?
Nikhil: Not everyone, like, you know, I want them to at least call another bugbear, or maybe two.
Nikhil: Can I ask you? That's what my expectation is, like, you know, if he…
Kostadis Roussos: But why… okay, so let me ask you a question. I mean, I just want to make sure. So…
Kostadis Roussos: there's this one guard. Is your plan to get everybody out and have a free-for-all fight, or what, like, what's your plan?
Nikhil: Yeah, I mean, I'm expecting at least…
Nikhil: one or two of them to come out, and then I want to engage in a fight.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, well, so, you know, Pip would have told you that the easiest way… that it's much better to silently kill the sentry, rather than to have everybody show up, because it might be more than two.
Kostadis Roussos: That's what Pip would say, but he also would be like, you're the one… you're the one, Pip, you know, it's like…
Kostadis Roussos: You haven't led us wrong yet, Zenvon.
Nikhil: I mean, it makes sense, but I'm thinking if we can kill him without…
Nikhil: Alerting others. Okay, yeah, I guess, I guess it doesn't matter either way, like, it's…
Nikhil: I feel using the mage hand is more effort.
Nikhil: For the same output.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I mean, you've got him distracted, like, now he's fully distracted, so you would… if you were trying to do a surprise attack, this might be the right time to do it.
Nikhil: Oh, right, yeah, yeah, yeah, okay, okay, yeah, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Remember, you guys get a big advantage when you have surprise, right?
Nikhil: Right, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So, if your plan was to ambush him, this is not a bad way to start up an ambush.
Nikhil: Okay, okay, yeah, yeah, makes sense.
Nikhil: So…
Kostadis Roussos: So, do you want to have them head more towards your guys, or do you want to have them head more away from your guys?
Nikhil: head more away from my guys, and then.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, hold on, if you send him away, then remember, Pip can't hit him, because he's too far away.
Nikhil: Well, no, no, no, what I meant is, like.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you want to go this arrow, this way, or this way? Which way? North or south?
Nikhil: No, he's gonna stay there, wherever he is.
Nikhil: But he just has the back turned towards Pip.
Nikhil: Because of the… Right, right.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, but the problem is, like, this is 60 feet of open territory.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And he's already suspected that somebody's over here. He's already… he's already heard something, so he's looking towards the south.
Nikhil: Okay, so… no, no, but is he distracted still if he's moving down south?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, he's… he's kind of staring down south, so now you have an opportunity to try to get… you can either… you can either confirm his suspicion and have him keep walking, see if you can get him to keep walking more south, or point him in a different direction.
Kostadis Roussos: The only thing I want to make sure you remember, because you're new to this combat, is that 60 feet, like, this represents the amount of distance Pip would have to cover before he could attack, and he can't… and he wouldn't be able to attack in the first round.
Nikhil: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm just trying, like, I just want to be like, the closer he gets to Pip, the better off you are. The further away he is from Pip, the worse… the harder it is to kill him in one round. That's my only point.
Nikhil: Okay, so, so when he suspects there is something towards the south behind the rock.
Nikhil: I throw a stone using mage hand from the north, and he turns his back around, and then I would want Pip to move, you know, somewhere here into the ridge.
Nikhil: like…
Kostadis Roussos: To attack.
Nikhil: In that time, like, you know, and sneak, and, you know, stay in position there.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, so, alright, so, he comes over here, Alright.
Nikhil: He comes over there. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And so, Wendy's over there, what is it that you do?
Nikhil: No, that's not what I meant, but
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, okay, so he, you threw… he…
Nikhil: He's there. Right, he's there.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he's there.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: He heard some noise from the south, because your guys blew their stealth check. He can't see them yet, so he's slow… he's moving… he's moving down. He's moved, like, 10 feet down.
Nikhil: Alright, okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: like, move, like, 10… let's say he's come to here.
Nikhil: What do you do?
Kostadis Roussos: He's got his poik in front of him, and he's looking, and you can see him looking over his shoulder, a Roland Insight check.
Nikhil: Sweet.
Nikhil: Kevin?
Kostadis Roussos: Right, you, you notice, nothing.
Nikhil: Tricky here.
Nikhil: Okay, I want to use, Veyra as a bait.
Nikhil: Because she… she looks like a… What'd you say?
Nikhil: Sorceress, like, you know, like a student?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Nikhil: Right, so I want Veyra to step out into the open and, so that the bugbear can notice her and walk a little forward.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, what did she say?
Nikhil: No, she doesn't say anything, she uses, like,
Nikhil: You know, she kind of shouting, like, I'm lost here, like, can you help me?
Nikhil: And that way, the bugbear is walking, like, 2 more…
Nikhil: Squares down south, and then…
Nikhil: I'll attack from the back, and Pip can attack from the front.
Nikhil: He's gonna put…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you're trying to… you're basically trying to make Veyra look like she's some lost academic who doesn't know what's going on, right?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah.
Nikhil: I'm trying to…
Kostadis Roussos: I'm trying to decide what Veyra's reaction is.
Nikhil: I thought a lot about this.
Kostadis Roussos: But, okay, Veyra, Veyra's kinda like…
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra, picks up, picks up her notebook, she looks at the bug beer, realizes the bug beer, she has enough time to dodge him, so she steps up and stands in front, stands in front.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, the only question is, do you want to make her to make noise, or do you just want her to be, like, look confused?
Nikhil: Anything is fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, if she makes noise, she might attract other people from the cave. Is your goal to get him.
Nikhil: Oh.
Nikhil: Yeah, so I think she just stands confused, not knowing what to do.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. So she, she, she, she sets up, she stands there, and she's got her notebook.
Nikhil: Yeah, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: the bugbearer… Caesar, and growls.
Kostadis Roussos: And takes…
Kostadis Roussos: takes a step forward, not sure what to do. Alright, let's roll for… let's, roll… let's roll to see what happens.
Nikhil: E20, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah, hold on.
Nikhil: Extreme?
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: So you rolled a 16?
Kostadis Roussos: Are you having fun with the spells?
Nikhil: Yeah, I'm just trying to check how to use, you know, the marker to point.
Kostadis Roussos: Six.
Kostadis Roussos: The one you're looking for is the, if you're looking for the pointer.
Nikhil: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You see where the hand is? If you click on the point at the… the… just above where it says the three…
Nikhil: Yes, yes. And double-click, it's not working.
Kostadis Roussos: No, you don't double-click, you just point. Click on hold.
Nikhil: Okay, okay, cool, okay, yeah, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: The bugbear… Grunt something, what language do they do? Grunt something in common.
Kostadis Roussos: muttering… Just a tourist!
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you're… so… so as far as, the… just… Just a tourist.
Kostadis Roussos: But he says it in the same way you might say, just a chicken I'm about to have dinner with.
Kostadis Roussos: Where I'm gonna be having dinner, and the chicken's gonna be the food.
Nikhil: Okay.
Nikhil: Okay, that's the motion, so cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Just to give you the idea of the motion right now, alright?
Nikhil: Yes, yes.
Nikhil: So if he gets the first turn… that's interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Kostadis Roussos: I was looking for Ember Spoon of chain. Alright, next, the next thing to do is to… Ember dog can't have frozen bagels anymore, she needs them thawed.
Kostadis Roussos: walking.
Kostadis Roussos: Thought the bagels.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I'm just sorry to hear about her teeth.
Kostadis Roussos: She's six and a half, and she chews all sorts of random rocks and sticks and bagels and bones, and this is not a… No, I know, I'm just sad. I'm sad for her teeth.
Kostadis Roussos: She's not gonna… she's not gonna… What's her bagel thought, please? Okay. She chipped a couple of chips in the… in her back, chewing teeth. That's fine, that's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, let's see… Okay, so roll your stealth with advantage.
Nikhil: I will click that line. Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Beppa? Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, those, eat those.
Nikhil: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: That's with advantage, that was… that means roll again.
Kostadis Roussos: Wow, you ruled really badly. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Veyra is the only one who gets a surprise round.
Nikhil: Oh.
Nikhil: So he notices me from the back.
Kostadis Roussos: No, you don't… well, you don't surprise him, is what I'm trying to say.
Kostadis Roussos: He notice… he notices you enough so you don't… you don't have, surprise.
Kostadis Roussos: Although, I guess, I guess if you're hidden, you'd still have a sneak attack bonus, so I'm gonna go with the…
Kostadis Roussos: You don't surprise him, but I'm going to say that you were hidden. Does that make sense?
Nikhil: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? Because he didn't notice you, so if you… you don't get a surprise round, which means you don't get to attack and then get it to attack before he gets to attack? Does that make sense?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah, totally.
Kostadis Roussos: So, Veyra's the only one who gets a surprise round. What does Veyra do? I have to get her character sheet.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh.
Kostadis Roussos: Damn.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Veyra… Shoots an arrow, uses magic missile on him.
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra, that was not very good. Alright, and does 6 points of damage with Magic Missile. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: the bug beer… And then she decides to… Pardon.
Kostadis Roussos: 2…
Nikhil: Can I… can I request a health bar on top of that?
Kostadis Roussos: But… Hold on, watch. The bug here goes 1, 2, 3, 4, 5… 6.
Kostadis Roussos: He sees Pip, Sister Maela, And… Veyra. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Zenvon Europe.
Nikhil: Yeah, can I request a helper on top of the bugbear?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, because you're… because you're hidden, you can use your, ranged attack to hit him with… and gain… you gain your sneak attack bonus.
Nikhil: That is fine. I'm asking, like, for a health bar on top of the bugbears, like, the bugbear's health bar.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, health bar!
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: I was hearing Helper.
Nikhil: Oh, no, not a helper, health bar, sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: That's right.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry.
Nikhil: Oh, cool, yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, Zenvon, you're up.
Nikhil: One of… I'm gonna use a shortbow?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Nikhil: So… Should do, alright.
Nikhil: Rolling for Chardo.
Nikhil: 7?
Kostadis Roussos: You're older 7.
Nikhil: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, this is…
Nikhil: That.
Kostadis Roussos: That is a miss.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Nikhil: No, I… That would be nice, like, can I get a second toy or something somehow?
Kostadis Roussos: No, but you might want to start running towards your party.
Nikhil: Totally agree.
Nikhil: Mmm…
Kostadis Roussos: The other… the other thing you… so remember, you have the ability to do bonus action.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you're gonna run over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Or are you gonna run over there?
Nikhil: Yeah, here is fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Here, so you're gonna run along the ridge.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Are you going to try… okay. I think… do you have a… do you have bonus actions that allow you to hide?
Nikhil: Do I have a bonus action that allows me to fight?
Nikhil: Dash dis… yes, yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you can choose to hide if you want.
Nikhil: Okay, I'll hide.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so let me just see if he knows… right. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Sister Maela… I was like… She looks at the, bugbear.
Kostadis Roussos: And says, turn… shouts, we can't let him get close to… we can't let him…
Kostadis Roussos: Warn the other guys.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, she marches up to him and hits him.
Kostadis Roussos: And at least she's… she smashes him with her mace.
Kostadis Roussos: It says, this is how it's done.
Kostadis Roussos: I understand what you should do.
Kostadis Roussos: She does, 6 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Stir… Maela. Right, sister, Maela… okay, that's it. Veyra.
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra… Looks at him again, and decides to cast another… Magic result.
Kostadis Roussos: And this time, she does 12 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: PIP.
Kostadis Roussos: Goes over here, goes over here… And uses his sword.
Kostadis Roussos: I need to even make sure I remember what… there's a sword. He has a special sword now, if I'm not mistaken.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me explain.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's got a plus one. Yeah, he's got a plus one,
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's got a plus one sword. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Good.
Kostadis Roussos: So, okay, so he's got plus 3 to a 10.
Kostadis Roussos: Listen, right?
Kostadis Roussos: plus 5 to 10, right? So, 20 plus 5.
Kostadis Roussos: Does that work?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he hits, which is good news. And,
Nikhil: space.
Kostadis Roussos: And he kills the bugbearer.
Nikhil: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, the bug beer is dead.
Kostadis Roussos: That's fair.
Nikhil: I feel a little bit sad for the bugbear.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela says, it's always a good thing to feel sad about killing one of, one of the creatures in this world, but when you're dealing with, but it was either us or him.
Nikhil: But… I feel sad because he was blind in one eye.
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra says, yeah, but I was his lunch.
Nikhil: I get it, that's okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela's like, that's very… it's very noble of you to, you know, to be… to be… to thoughtfully care
Kostadis Roussos: About the bugbearers, that, that is, that is to your credit.
Nikhil: Oh, well, okay, let's… Let's move on.
Nikhil: Like, what can we do now?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: what can we do now, right? So, Sister Maela says, well, if we leave the body here, and somebody comes out, they may notice… they may notice… they may… they might… all of our effort to try to get some kind of surprise might go to waste.
Nikhil: Okay, let's hide in the bushes, hide the body in the bushes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you're gonna hide the body in the bushes?
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so we'll put a… Bugs of your body.
Nikhil: Right here, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Marketing bed.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Hey, now what do you want to do?
Nikhil: Mmm…
Kostadis Roussos: Go peek inside.
Nikhil: Yeah.
Nikhil: I guess?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: Yeah, I can't move her.
Kostadis Roussos: Who? Can't… who can't you move?
Nikhil: Omega.
Nikhil: Totally.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on. Yeah, let me just go fix that. Let me go fix that now.
Nikhil: Oh yeah, I think I can. Cool.
Kostadis Roussos: You get enough?
Nikhil: Thank you.
Kostadis Roussos: Awesome. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: That was… oh, they fixed it! Oh my god! There was this bug where you would change… make the change, but then you had to create, like, even though it was linked to that token, you had to, like.
Kostadis Roussos: remove the token and add it. I was like, that used to drive me nuts that they couldn't get that feature to work.
Nikhil: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, part of the reason why I kept not doing it is because getting it to work always involved, like.
Kostadis Roussos: It was very finicky.
Kostadis Roussos: But apparently somebody decided to go fix it. Alright, Zenvon, you wanna go look inside?
Nikhil: Wait, hold on, let me see…
Kostadis Roussos: I think you have a potion of invisibility.
Nikhil: Aye… cannot see in the dark, right? Or can I see in the dark?
Kostadis Roussos: No, but it's not dark. I mean, you can… it's not, black, because there's a fire, remember?
Nikhil: Right, okay, okay. So, yeah, I wanna, like, take a peek.
Nikhil: Alright, so…
Kostadis Roussos: I'm gonna take a peek.
Kostadis Roussos: It's a lot like pitch… pitch black.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alrighty.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So you sort of peek inside there.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: You see a bunch of, you notice a bunch of things, right? There's 4 bugbeers, there's an ogre.
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And there's this one orc.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I will make sure that I'm just…
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see… let me just see what… how this… It's okay.
Nikhil: Why is the ogre big?
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, give me one sec.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so as you look around, a role… role in investigation.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okie dokie. Sister Maela, you don't notice anything, so Sister Maela pokes her head as well.
Kostadis Roussos: She's like, she doesn't notice anything, which causes Pip to, of course want to take a look as well.
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: He notices that…
Kostadis Roussos: the… he's a military man, right? So he notices… he looks around and says, you know, what's interesting about this group is that, the orc.
Kostadis Roussos: is the weakest of all of these characters, and yet, he seems to be the only one that has any authority here. Like, normally, an ogre's in charge. So I don't know, but this seems like a very interesting situation.
Nikhil: How does he confirm that the orc is in… Authority here.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, he, he goes, look… now he tried to… he goes, now, now look, Zenvon, in the military, sometimes the, the, the, the, the, most of these creatures are… respond to whoever's the biggest, so normally it would be the ogre in charge.
Kostadis Roussos: And an orc would be, kind of, like, bringing them food left, right, and center.
Kostadis Roussos: But if you look in… right, but if you look inside, he's the one sitting next to the fire.
Kostadis Roussos: And everybody's sort of listening to him.
Nikhil: Okay, that's a brilliant observation.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes, and so, I'm just gonna tell you that that tells me that he's the brains of the operation.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: So… You know, I don't want to tell you how to do your job.
Kostadis Roussos: But,
Kostadis Roussos: My experience is with these kind of groups, and not with these kind of groups, but in the army, if you kill the leader in this kind of group, it's kind of a mob, it's kind of a gang. If you kill the gang boss, everybody else suddenly doesn't want to fight anymore.
Nikhil: That makes our job interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: I just wanna throw that… I just wanna throw that out there, boss.
Kostadis Roussos: Or, you know, we could run in there and try to kill them all. Last time we faced 4 bugbeers, we had to run for our lives, so I'm not entirely certain that's something we want to do.
Nikhil: Well, you make a point, but that's,
Nikhil: pretty valid. So, what do you suggest? Do you suggest, to kill the orc?
Nikhil: From this far, or do you…
Nikhil: Wanna confront him, because if we confront him, like, he's gonna…
Nikhil: How about it has alert the bugbears and the oak.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela goes, Looks at him a little bit carefully and says.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see what you should say.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, let me have a look at what… let me have a look at the situation, she says.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: So, I can create any illusions, right?
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Nikhil: Mmm, and I will be hidden behind the illusion.
Kostadis Roussos: I'm sorry?
Nikhil: Will I be hidden behind the illusion I create?
Nikhil: Let's suppose I create a…
Kostadis Roussos: No, I mean…
Nikhil: football, and… Can I be seen behind the football?
Kostadis Roussos: No.
Kostadis Roussos: You cannot be seen behind the football.
Nikhil: Okay, I have a weird idea. I want to create an illusion of the…
Nikhil: You know, the guarding bugbear, and word?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, keep going.
Nikhil: Yeah, I want to create an illusion of the guarding bugbear, and then all four of us walk behind him.
Nikhil: Without being seen.
Nikhil: To the orc.
Kostadis Roussos: I mean, just to be clear, you all have ranged weapons.
Nikhil: We do, but, you know, I'm afraid, like, within… with just one attack, I don't think we can kill.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so… okay, so you guys want to, like, gang up on him, right?
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: Cool.
Kostadis Roussos: So, the only problem is the illusion, I believe, is stationary.
Nikhil: Stationary.
Nikhil: Says minor illusion.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so what is it? What's the spell called?
Nikhil: Minor illusion?
Nikhil: You create a sound or an image of an object within range that lasts for the duration.
Nikhil: See the descriptions below?
Kostadis Roussos: No movement.
Nikhil: It must be no larger than a 5-foot cube. The image can't create sound.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so it's… 5 foot cube means it could be the shape of a bugbear. So you could create a bugbear image that you could make sure that you make an illusion of the bugbear over here. Let me just put… let me just draw it here, right? So you make an illusion of the bugbear over here, so that… and then you could rush the illusion, right? Does that make sense?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: You can't hide behind it, so what you're essentially trying to do is use that to get us… to surprise him.
Nikhil: I… why cannot I hide behind him?
Kostadis Roussos: But you can't… he doesn't move.
Nikhil: No, he moves. I mean, there's no way written that he cannot move.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yes, if you look at the illusion, the minor illusion, maybe I'm looking at the wrong definition of the spell, hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Build them!
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, holy.
Kostadis Roussos: It's entirely possible that I am looking at the wrong definition of these spells.
Nikhil: fusion contract.
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Spell minor illusion.
Kostadis Roussos: You create a sound or image of an object that lasts for a round. Creature takes an action, blah blah blah, sound…
Nikhil: Yeah, so physical interaction reveals that it's an illusion, but otherwise it can move.
Kostadis Roussos: No, it doesn't say you can't move it.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just check something again.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so you can't move it. It does not support movement. It's cast… you create a sound within an object that lasts for the duration, so no, you cannot have it move.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so that… I read the rules. That is not one of the things that this spell allows you to do.
Nikhil: But we can hide behind it, and charge.
Nikhil: Yes, that's true.
Kostadis Roussos: So, yeah, you can definitely do that, and certainly if you put them there.
Kostadis Roussos: I will give you an advantage on your, stealth.
Kostadis Roussos: to attack him.
Nikhil: Okay, perfect.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Nikhil: Awesome. Let's do that.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that is a very clever solution to the problem.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And you just go to the roll 20,
Kostadis Roussos: That was a very clever solution to the problem. All right. Okay. So, Veyra's gonna be over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela… It's gonna be over here. Zenvon.
Kostadis Roussos: I'll, just do this.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, why don't you guys, roll your, stealth with… initiative, with,
Nikhil: Advantage.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, with Advantage. Let's see, can you guys do better this time?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, good.
Nikhil: Got it.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, I was Sister Maela.
Nikhil: with it, yeah, with advantage, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you, you, yeah, you definitely crossed the threshold.
Kostadis Roussos: 2d20.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela did as well.
Kostadis Roussos: Hoop.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip did not.
Kostadis Roussos: And what about… okay, so… 2… 2…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, Zenvon and Sister Maela get to attack with surprise. Pip and Veyra have to wait for their turn in the normal initiative order.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, let's give…
Kostadis Roussos: Can you roll, can you roll your initiative, can you roll your initiative? John, we can keep your old initiatives, or you can re-roll, it's up to you.
Nikhil: I'll rule out for, okay, no.
Kostadis Roussos: You wanna re-roll? R-roll, re-roll, it's always fun to roll the dice.
Nikhil: Hmm. Okay, one more, please, sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: What did you roll?
Nikhil: Happy with this.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: That's not what I wanted.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Zenvon.
Kostadis Roussos: Are you gonna rush in to try to kill the guy?
Nikhil: Yes, I'm gonna,
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you have surprise, so you can attack him with your sneak attack bonus.
Nikhil: Yep.
Nikhil: Yeah, so I was gonna use the… Nick?
Nikhil: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So you can move away?
Nikhil: Not move… okay, wait, I'll use my VEX, so that I can hit twice.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you hit get advantage on the second roll, right?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, go for it.
Nikhil: Shotswold, yes, okay, I'm gonna use my short sword,
Kostadis Roussos: That is a hit.
Nikhil: What does that hinge.
Kostadis Roussos: And if you click the roll damages in Roll20, that… it'll tell you what… it'll roll the damages from there.
Nikhil: Okay, fine.
Kostadis Roussos: 7 points of damage. Not exactly the best roll you could have had.
Nikhil: Yeah, and then I have the… Have a night.
Kostadis Roussos: Yep.
Nikhil: Rolling again, 14.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that is also a hit.
Nikhil: Okay, rolling for damages… 7.
Kostadis Roussos: He's down to one hit point.
Nikhil: Oh, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: We established Sister Maela had advantage, right? So, Sister Maela…
Kostadis Roussos: Comes in 1, 2, 3, 4.
Kostadis Roussos: 5…
Nikhil: Wait, the second attack was supposed to be an advantage for me, right? I did not…
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, roll, roll with advantage, yes, roll, roll a second time? RT20?
Nikhil: That's a miss. I guess.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, that would… that would have been a mess. Alright, she's actually got 2 hit points, I miscalculated it. Okay, so she's got 2 hit points. Sister Maela.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela, you're breaking my heart, lady.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Jeez, Sister Maela, you broke my heart.
Nikhil: Yes, you did.
Nikhil: I guess it's picked next.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so… Shall I take this backstage one of these bugbars?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so she misses, so…
Nikhil: Oh, there's a 15, right?
Kostadis Roussos: No, I… I just… I'm just… I realize when you have a surprise, the rules are different than they used… than I used to remember them, so I just had to re-change something. All right.
Nikhil: Yay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, okay, so now we go through the initiative normally. Sister Maela, you're up.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, Zenvon, you're up again.
Nikhil: I'll use the short for it again.
Kostadis Roussos: You… by the way, because this… yeah, go for it, go.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, roll to hit. That's a miss. Roll to hit again?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: Advantage, or no?
Kostadis Roussos: You don't have… oh, yeah, you do have Advantage, yes, yes, now you have Advantage, yes.
Nikhil: Okay, so rolling again.
Nikhil: Hey, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes!
Nikhil: Okay. Yes.
Nikhil: And they're rolling for attacks. Oh, wow, he's dead. Meeting.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, he's not just dead, right? Like, you take your sword… this is the Scimitar, right?
Nikhil: It's a short sword.
Kostadis Roussos: No, you use your sort… you have to sort, sort, sort, and a scimitar. Remember, you have one in each hand?
Nikhil: Huh.
Kostadis Roussos: Doesn't… they do the same amount of damage.
Nikhil: Okay, oh, yes, yes, yeah, yeah, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And so, you hit him with the short sword, and he kind of loses his balance, and then you take your scimitar and just, like, cut his throat open, and he splatters…
Kostadis Roussos: He reaches for his neck… he reaches for his neck dead. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see what happens… okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me… let me just make sure I know what happens.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So,
Nikhil: And you'll just want.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: This bug beer kind of was like…
Nikhil: Check out this YouTube video.
Kostadis Roussos: Which one?
Nikhil: The one I sent in the chat.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, and which chat?
Nikhil: Zoom chat, sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: I asked, like, welcome to the… this… every time I use this, I feel like I'm using Google products.
Nikhil: City?
Nikhil: That's the Hague.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: That's the scene.
Kostadis Roussos: That is definitely… that is definitely the vibe. Alright, where were we?
Nikhil: is dead, we both are inside. Pip and Veyra are outside, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, hold on. So, okay, so this bug we were seeing him die at goes, I'm outta here at 13.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, he's running away. Now, do you… if you attack him, he's gonna stop running away. Do you let him run away?
Nikhil: Why is he running, like, outside, or, like, into the cave somewhere?
Kostadis Roussos: No, he's running outside, he's like, I'm done.
Nikhil: What about the other bugbears?
Nikhil: Have they noticed this?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, yeah, they just saw their boss killed, right?
Nikhil: So, all of them, including the ogre.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so everybody's noticed, and so the re… so take… if you want to use your insight, use your insight for a moment.
Nikhil: Yeah, I'm gonna use my website.
Nikhil: I don't get anything.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, that's… that's bad. Alright.
Nikhil: Can I use my perception?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, roll your, roll your perception.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay. What you notice… what you perceive is that the bugbearers kind of are, like, I'm at, like, see him dead, and, like, just want to get out of here.
Kostadis Roussos: The ogre is furious and wants to go kill you.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Nikhil: Mmm… Okay, I'll let the bugbears, run away then.
Kostadis Roussos: You're gonna let the lit bugbrews run away?
Nikhil: Yeah, just fight with the over.
Kostadis Roussos: So, he runs out here, runs through here, Pip and Veyra.
Kostadis Roussos: Let him get… let him run away.
Kostadis Roussos: Right. Veyra's about to try to kill him, and Pip reminds her what the plan was.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? Remember, Veyra has a thing with killing people, right?
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Sister Maela… Seeing, the ogre, the, the bugbear dead.
Kostadis Roussos: Shouts, you know, if you want to live, be somewhere else.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: the bugbears get the point, and, kind of make… don't get in her way. The ogre is kind of pissed off, calling them a bunch of cowards, and, you know, blah blah blah, and that his beloved,
Kostadis Roussos: Brughor, Axe-Biter, whom he loved dearly, and you killed him, you bastards.
Nikhil: So what's he gonna do next after?
Kostadis Roussos: Well, I'm… Maela's gonna attack, is what's gonna happen. Okay. So, Sister Maela's going to attack.
Kostadis Roussos: But no, what I'm trying to tell you is that he's emotion… apparently he was emotionally invested.
Nikhil: In the book.
Kostadis Roussos: In the bugroom.
Nikhil: No, no.
Kostadis Roussos: In, in, in, what's his name?
Nikhil: R.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: The orc, the orc. Yeah, the orc.
Kostadis Roussos: Where is this?
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just get my… let me open her character sheet so I don't keep my life a little bit easier.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so she's going to use, her Sacred Flame.
Kostadis Roussos: And he blows it, so he takes 2d8 Rick, takes 10 points of damage.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, and she does it from over here. So she calls on Sacred Flame.
Kostadis Roussos: And it falls on his head. The ogre howls.
Kostadis Roussos: A mini dog, you kill, Brughor, me eat you alive.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Another bug beer runs out.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip, it's Pip's turn.
Nikhil: Pip is outside.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so Pip comes over here…
Kostadis Roussos: And runs over here, and, decides that this is a good time to not miss.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: He's like, please, baby, don't let me miss.
Nikhil: Yep.
Nikhil: Oh, he also has that, you know… The fancy sword?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, he's got a plus one magical sword, that is true.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: What heck does he do?
Kostadis Roussos: Where's his, where's his damage? Okay, D4 plus 5. Alright. So… hip.
Kostadis Roussos: Strikes with his, sword.
Kostadis Roussos: Wait, that's fine.
Kostadis Roussos: Is he hit?
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he hits.
Kostadis Roussos: Or, 58…
Kostadis Roussos: 8 plus 3.
Kostadis Roussos: 6 points of damage.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, he's going to use an action surge.
Kostadis Roussos: And he misses on his second attack.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Just… These two guys have gone to the wind.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: The next bugbear… This one also runs out, and, you know… He's gone to the wind.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Gog. It's Gog's turn now, isn't it?
Kostadis Roussos: GOG. Alright, GOG.
Kostadis Roussos: Or, Ray's is this great club.
Kostadis Roussos: And tries to bring it down on Pip, and misses. How could I miss? Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: This bugbearer also decides he's, you know, there's a time and a place for bravery, and this is not it.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: It's kind of weird, like, you know, that normally these guys should have been able to handle, so there's something… there's something weird going on about these four bugbears, and this ogre that you don't know. All right,
Kostadis Roussos: is, let's get rid of him, alright. Veyra.
Kostadis Roussos: ZRA steps over here… Let's see what her spell situation is like.
Kostadis Roussos: Telled her to use magic missile twice, so she's gonna use a Firebolt.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Nikhil: Let me move this part of the way.
Kostadis Roussos: So it's just going to… No, he can be there. She, she's the firebolt… okay.
Kostadis Roussos: 5 foot cubed.
Kostadis Roussos: Is, like, this much as volume.
Nikhil: Right, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Buyer Bolt is this big.
Nikhil: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You… Veyra can aim through you.
Kostadis Roussos: This is not first edition rules, alright?
Kostadis Roussos: Where, actually, there was a 50% chance you would get hit, regardless if you hit roll. Alright,
Kostadis Roussos: She hits him for… One glorious point of damage.
Nikhil: Oh, shit. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Zenvon, you're up next.
Nikhil: I wanna use the spell Truestrike.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so that's what you're… is… okay.
Nikhil: I've never done it, so it's my first time. Let's see what happens.
Nikhil: The attack uses your spellcasting ability for the attack and damage rolls, instead of using strength or dexterity.
Nikhil: So lots of spellcasting?
Nikhil: Arcana?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, if you go to your character sheet.
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Can you look above it, like, where you look where it says spells, the spells you can cast?
Kostadis Roussos: If you show me your screen, I'll show you where it is.
Nikhil: Not a second.
Nikhil: You see it?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So, you see, this one?
Nikhil: No, right, right, yeah, yeah, this one, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, stop sharing.
Kostadis Roussos: So instead of using your normal to hit, you use plus 4, you use that.
Nikhil: Okay, so it's 23.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: And that is…
Nikhil: I believe it's a hit, and then should I roll for damage again, or is this for the damage?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you get… add plus 4 to hit, and then plus 4 to damage, so what did you… what did you attack with?
Nikhil: Fluestrike?
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Nikhil: I can use the radiant effect.
Nikhil: So, damaged.
Nikhil: Hold on, I mean… True strike, okay.
Nikhil: Oh my god.
Nikhil: One second, I need your help again.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, no, okay, okay, so let's pause you for a minute.
Kostadis Roussos: What weapon are you using to… hold on, my son's asking me for something, give me one second.
Kostadis Roussos: I got distracted.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: I'm gonna share my screen once I need your help to understand what's happening.
Nikhil: So… I clicked on this. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Very sad.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so let me… yes.
Nikhil: And I got this one, so I have to select a D20.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, you click on… click on… no, no. So, alright, for… to do the damage…
Kostadis Roussos: Right? You don't have to click on the radiant. That is just to… that is not what you have to click on.
Kostadis Roussos: You just click over here.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh.
Nikhil: Okay, no worries.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Nikhil: Still brings this one.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, what does it do?
Nikhil: I can choose a dice.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on, let me give you a sigh, let me sing.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, so the way you do it is you do… to do your attack, you click on this button over here.
Nikhil: Yes, that's what I did first. I got 23.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, then for damage… Right? You would roll a…
Kostadis Roussos: What webinar are you using? Go to Actions.
Nikhil: I'll use a short sword…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so what you do is you just roll… so the easiest thing to… if you're using a short sword, right? Yeah. It would be D6 plus 4 instead of plus 3, does that make sense?
Nikhil: Okay, okay, yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: So just add one to whatever you roll.
Nikhil: Okay, so I'll click this.
Nikhil: role,
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, you can click on the short sword damage and add one, because…
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, whatever it rolled, add 1.
Nikhil: 12.
Kostadis Roussos: 12 points of damage. What did you… you attacked with your short sword, right?
Kostadis Roussos: You can… Stop sharing now if you want.
Nikhil: Okay, thanks.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, with your short sword, is that what you did? So you rushed up to here and hit him with your short sword for 12 points of damage. Yep. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Now, do you want to attack again, because you… with your scimitar?
Nikhil: Yes, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Nikhil: 9 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: No, that was a miss, remember? You have to roll to hit.
Nikhil: Oh, okay, okay, let me…
Kostadis Roussos: You rolled damage, you unrolled your…
Nikhil: Yeah, natural 20 years.
Kostadis Roussos: Roll a natural 20. Alright, so that is… so the way you do a natural 20 is… if you click… just click… do you see where it says roll damages in the roll 20?
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah, no, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Just click that button.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, and so it's total damages…
Kostadis Roussos: 10 points of damage, because you already used your critical damage. Your critical attack. Your sneak attack, so you do 10 points of damage.
Kostadis Roussos: To help you understand how this… how this works, because it's, like, non-obvious.
Kostadis Roussos: See the first one that says slashing damage?
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: That's how much you do from your weapon, right? Your sneak attack…
Nikhil: tour.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, sneak attack damage, you know what that is.
Nikhil: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: The critical damage is you basically roll another D6.
Kostadis Roussos: And your sneak attack critical damage is you basically roll your sneak attack damage again.
Kostadis Roussos: And so that's how you get to 29.
Nikhil: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, but because you've already used your sneak attack bonus, you only add the slashing damage and the slashing critical damage. Does that make sense?
Nikhil: Makes sense, yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: It's just, you know, we're doing math. All right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Nikhil: Dean?
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so she's down to 20. You can use… you can see his, health bar, right?
Nikhil: No.
Kostadis Roussos: There we go.
Nikhil: Yeah, I see it now, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: It's such a huge creature, like…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah. Sister Maela uses her sacred flame again, and
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see, does, he make a saving throw?
Kostadis Roussos: No, he makes the same throw. Alright, pip.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Pip's already used is, there's a bonus, so… He misses. Alright, GOG.
Kostadis Roussos: Swings his… swings his… his mace.
Kostadis Roussos: And a missus. Alright, Veyra.
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra turns… shouts, hey boss, should I use my last spell?
Nikhil: Go ahead, make it count.
Kostadis Roussos: Make… make it count. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: She uses her, last magic missile, and this time does 15 points of damage.
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, Zenvon, you're up.
Nikhil: Before I kill him, I want to get some information from him, if I can, so…
Nikhil: Since he's almost to his knees, I wanna talk before attacking. Is that okay?
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on, you can… give me a sec. It's definitely… that is definitely an option.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so, what are you gonna try to do?
Nikhil: Does he have a name?
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, yes, you did hear his name. You did refer to himself as Gog.
Nikhil: Gog, yes, yes. Hey, Gog, Visem,
Nikhil: We did not intend to hurt you or your boss, but
Nikhil: We had to help our friend Hamun Kost.
Nikhil: Like, and also protect the land from… All the, you know.
Nikhil: Threats and the robberies that you guys have been doing.
Nikhil: I just wanted to know before, you know.
Nikhil: We finished the business, like, why are we doing, and do you know…
Nikhil: Anything about hormone costs? Tell us what has happened in the past.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright? Are you trying to… you're trying to do it diplomatically, so roll your persuasion.
Nikhil: Switching, okay…
Nikhil: Natural 20… 22…
Kostadis Roussos: Did you roll a natural 20?
Nikhil: Yes, sir.
Kostadis Roussos: All right. I think that's… hold on, let me get something to drink. Hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: One second.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, so, your question, your ques… you go…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you asked… what is it that you asked him? Just, remind me?
Nikhil: I wanted to know… no, I just tell them that we are…
Nikhil: Here to help our friend Hamun Kost, and if he…
Nikhil: Now, what is the story behind, you know, the relationship between the skies and the hormone costs, like…
Nikhil: Hamun mentioned that you guys… these guys have been bothering him, so…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so why have you been bothering? Okay, so he looks at you and goes.
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at you and goes, You killed Brughor! Brughor!
Kostadis Roussos: And you can gather that they had some kind of romantic relationship. It's kind of awkward.
Kostadis Roussos: and he looks at you and goes, Brughor!
Kostadis Roussos: Brughor say, Brughor, pause, Brughor, He starts crying.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: He looks at you… he looks at you and goes, Brughor say, attack.
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… he looks at you, goes, who the heck is… he doesn't know who Hamun Kost is, so you're gonna have to describe them to him.
Nikhil: Okay. Oh, okay. Interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: He doesn't know who he is.
Nikhil: So Brughor says they attack, and they attack, that's it, okay. So this guy, he doesn't know anything.
Nikhil: Fine, kill him. I will.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay! You're cold, man.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela's like, sounds good to me. I never liked ogres.
Nikhil: cast.
Kostadis Roussos: She makes her, saving throw. Gog is outraged.
Kostadis Roussos: And enraged at this point in time. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip, Pip, it's Pip's turn.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: It's a hit.
Kostadis Roussos: And kills him.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela, turn… you… do you applaud? Do you, like, literally clap your hands?
Nikhil: Yeah, good job, Sister Maela.
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, that was PIP.
Nikhil: Oh, that was PIP, yes, sorry.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela looks at you and goes, dude, you're cold.
Nikhil: I have to be sometimes, you know?
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, you are really cold, man.
Nikhil: Did you just forget that I was feeling bad for killing the bugbear who was blind?
Kostadis Roussos: She pauses and goes.
Kostadis Roussos: I didn't say you weren't kind, I mean, but that was cold. You try to negotiate with him, decides he has nothing to add, and that's just kill him?
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: pauses. Personally, I wouldn't have wasted time on the negotiation, I would have just killed him, but, you know…
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra is very pleased. Alright, you wanna keep looking around?
Nikhil: Yeah, of course, they robbed a lot of people, so there must be a lot of treasures around.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, shouldn't therapy?
Nikhil: So I go to this corner.
Nikhil: It goes to this courtroom.
Nikhil: There it goes here.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Nikhil: Yeah.
Nikhil: Every four are searching the cave.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, you're searching the cave.
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, as, as,
Kostadis Roussos: As pit… as was San Juan.
Kostadis Roussos: Nothing, I just was trying to find… see where you guys went.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so…
Kostadis Roussos: As you're… as you're walking around, You notice a strange… A strange drawing.
Nikhil: Growing, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: on the walls.
Nikhil: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: You see, first, you see, it's made of charcoal.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you get… do you step back to look at it, or… or do you ignore it?
Nikhil: do I want to look at it?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: It's a figure. You notice it's a figure.
Kostadis Roussos: As you stare at it some more…
Kostadis Roussos: As you stared at some more… you notice…
Kostadis Roussos: That it's a… looks like a goblin.
Kostadis Roussos: But as you look at it some more, you notice it has a crystal jutting from its skull.
Nikhil: Black crystal?
Kostadis Roussos: Nope. A crystal, it's in charcoal. I mean, it could be black, but it's…
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so, so imagine… here, let me just,
Kostadis Roussos: Let me see.
Kostadis Roussos: Boom.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so imagine, like… let me see if I can do this by hand. Here, I'll do it in the little 20.
Kostadis Roussos: So, it's, like…
Nikhil: So the crystal, is that real, or is that also drawn in charcoal?
Kostadis Roussos: It's all… it's John and Charcoal.
Nikhil: Oh, I see, okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And the other thing you notice, Yeah, so… You see a goblin with… Abe…
Kostadis Roussos: Slightly off shape, but you don't know if that's a child's… if that's just a bad artist, and with a crystal on it.
Nikhil: Okay, okay.
Nikhil: I'm gonna call… Veyra?
Nikhil: Come look over the… I see, I see a drawing here on the wall.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Nikhil: Does this figure seem familiar from one of the books that you have read?
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: per…
Kostadis Roussos: So, her crystal flares.
Nikhil: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: faintly.
Kostadis Roussos: She looks at it and goes, Ha.
Kostadis Roussos: And reminds… and she goes… she looks and goes, this is the third such strange goblin we've seen.
Kostadis Roussos: Remember Sil… remember what Sildar told us?
Nikhil: No.
Kostadis Roussos: She pulls out her notes.
Kostadis Roussos: Because that's what she does. She keeps notes.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just see… She says…
Kostadis Roussos: I don't want to reveal too much.
Kostadis Roussos: No, that's not what I wanted. They seem…
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: So…
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, I put this in the… I put this in the Discord chat.
Kostadis Roussos: This is what, Sildar told you when he was, when he was captured.
Nikhil: Strange problem with an elongated head was with the cragmaw band, but we gave it… Let's look at that.
Nikhil: The goggling gives her a bad feeling.
Kostadis Roussos: So when Veyra had written that name last time, the crystal had blown.
Kostadis Roussos: upload.
Nikhil: You're not what Ruxithid wants.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip, goes over here and says, well, that's interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: But he's not actually talking about the statues, he's talking about the treasure he found.
Nikhil: Oh.
Nikhil: Well, he's a warrior, so… Yes, right.
Kostadis Roussos: He finds… He finds an unlocked treasure chest.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And,
Kostadis Roussos: So he goes, well, thank God. He goes, well, it's good… it's a good thing that Harbin Wester was gonna give us some money.
Nikhil: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Do you know why?
Nikhil: No.
Kostadis Roussos: That's why I said, like, look at this. This is a disgrace. What kind of bandit only has 180 silver pieces, 15 electrum pieces, and 3 bottles of perfume?
Nikhil: That seems odd for people who have, robbed… for, you know, for bandits who have robbed a lot of
Nikhil: Travelers.
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra goes, You do remember that nobody comes this way, right?
Nikhil: Right, but these guys, I guess they…
Nikhil: They attack all the travelers on the… I wait, I suppose.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, she's.
Nikhil: This is just their hideout.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you know, she goes… she pauses and says, That's a really good connection!
Kostadis Roussos: So, hear me out. I've got this crazy idea.
Nikhil: Go on.
Kostadis Roussos: It's all connected. The bugbeers, the strange goblins, the crystals… my mentor…
Kostadis Roussos: And she starts drawing connection after connection after connection.
Nikhil: Oh, wow, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, and, you know, she's like, she starts… she shows you this picture where she's got goblins pointing, you know, the.
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah, the detective thing.
Kostadis Roussos: What?
Kostadis Roussos: Maela looks it over and says, I think you're missing an arrow.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: She looks at it, she looks at him, and she stands there. Where? And Maela's laughing, because…
Kostadis Roussos: she knows that Veyra's gonna spend the next 20 minutes trying to find out which connection.
Nikhil: Oh, shit. Right.
Nikhil: So does the connections make sense, or do I need to know the connections?
Kostadis Roussos: You can… you… so… so you roll… and so you can ask her.
Nikhil: Okay, role, insight.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Nikhil: 18. Oh, sorry, it's a 5.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, no, it makes no sense to you.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And from Veyra… and you can't tell whether Veyra is just, like, trying to see patterns where they don't exist.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Kostadis Roussos: Or there are real patterns.
Nikhil: Yeah, I'm not sure, it makes sense to me, where…
Nikhil: What's the final conclusion of your connection?
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, I don't know, but it all points to somebody in charge doing something awful.
Nikhil: Well, I guess Hamun can give us more information about that, and I guess… Things are…
Nikhil: Lying in the Cragmaw closure.
Nikhil: And that's where we can find our answers.
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, EXACTLY! And so she puts, that's the arrow that's missing.
Kostadis Roussos: And so she… she draws a little castle, and then starts… points all the arrows to the castle.
Nikhil: Look houses, okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: That's where we have to go.
Nikhil: Okay.
Nikhil: Sister…
Kostadis Roussos: And she looks at Sister Maela with this look of, I found it.
Nikhil: Right, yeah. A sense of pride.
Kostadis Roussos: No, you know, a sense of, you know, I… I found the missing arrow.
Nikhil: Right, yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Sister Maela… Sister Maela's got that look of…
Kostadis Roussos: You know, just, like, sighing, closing her eyes. She says a little prayer to her god because she wants to avoid saying anything mean and nasty. All right. Okay, let me just mark down the treasure.
Kostadis Roussos: I have a Google spreadsheet, right? We have a Google spreadsheet for this.
Kostadis Roussos: No, I don't have a Google sheet.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, that's because I don't need Google Sheets anymore.
Kostadis Roussos: I'll put it in the Discord.
Nikhil: We were putting in the Discord chat earlier.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So, 160 silver pieces, 15 electrum pieces, 3 times 5 vials of
Kostadis Roussos: perfume.
Kostadis Roussos: 5GP each. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Not exactly… not exactly the big robbers here.
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: I presume…
Nikhil: So, do you wanna head back to Hamun and then, get the information about Cragmaw Castle?
Kostadis Roussos: Probably not a bad idea.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: Before we leave, Pip, since you killed the, or auger.
Nikhil: I wanna… Give you half of the silver pieces, and
Nikhil: One of the vials of the perfume.
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra, goes, boss?
Kostadis Roussos: I thought this was a group where we split things evenly.
Nikhil: Sure, but the auger was very big, and he got the last kill, so I thought, you know, maybe… and I've not done anything football too long. It's not that you guys will not get anything, but…
Nikhil: The next, you know, maybe whoever gets the last kill.
Kostadis Roussos: so is this what we're doing now? There's kill bonuses?
Nikhil: I'm just in a happy mood, so…
Kostadis Roussos: She goes, well, why don't you give them from your share, and we'll get them normal share?
Nikhil: Sure, okay, Pip, here's what we'll do. You can have my share, and they'll get their share.
Kostadis Roussos: Everybody's very happy now.
Nikhil: Yes, awesome, okay. I did my share to Pip.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, that sounds like a plan.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, you head over to, the Old Owl well.
Nikhil: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Nikhil: He knows a moon.
Nikhil: Moon is here.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, is that right?
Nikhil: So, this.
Kostadis Roussos: Hold on, hold on, hold on, hold on, let me just make sure… you should be able to see him, right?
Nikhil: I can see the numbers.
Nikhil: my shout, without, you know, catching the attention of the zombies.
Nikhil: And ask Hamun to come out.
Nikhil: Tell him that, the threat at Wyvern Tor has been… mitigated.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, the, the zombies are all in here.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just say, as a, you know, as you head back, you remember, you remember some of the zombies that you saw looked a little bit different.
Nikhil: Oh, you know, huh?
Kostadis Roussos: Like, one of them looked like a red wizard.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay? Meaning that it was somebody, obviously, who came with him.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: And, another guy, another zombie over here looks like,
Kostadis Roussos: He was a guard of some kind.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? The rest of them look like general…
Kostadis Roussos: peasants, that happened to have been in the wrong place at the wrong time with a powerful wizard, red wizard. Amun is delighted, Hamun sees you, and he says.
Kostadis Roussos: Tell me, tell me, Pip, what, what, sorry, Zenvon, tell me what news you have. Tell me only good news.
Nikhil: Well, Hamun, the good news is the threat has been,
Nikhil: extinguished at the Wyvern Tor. We killed the boss, and the…
Nikhil: The ogre, and the bugbears ran away.
Nikhil: What?
Kostadis Roussos: Wonderful! Wonderful, wonderful, wonderful. And if I recall, I promised you a meal.
Nikhil: Yes, and also some information.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, well, it's uncivilized to not have the meal first.
Nikhil: Sure, yeah, we were…
Kostadis Roussos: He claps his hands. He claps his… he claps his hands.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And he's, it's a very good meal.
Nikhil: Right, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: And so, one of the things that you notice about, like, it's a very good meal, and, like, it's kind of, like, bizarre that this guy…
Kostadis Roussos: Has spent this much money on this meal.
Nikhil: Hmm, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Rather, like, not so much on the meal, like, on the…
Kostadis Roussos: Let's see, I need something…
Nikhil: In the serving part?
Kostadis Roussos: No, hold on.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so, no, he's obviously somebody who enjoys the finer things in life.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? And so… and one of the zombies is sort of, the red wizard zombie is… is sort of acting as the waiter. So you basically have this,
Kostadis Roussos: Zombie serving you food.
Nikhil: Great.
Kostadis Roussos: It's very, kind of, like, creepy.
Kostadis Roussos: he's, they're sitting around this table, having dinner, there's a nice little fire. Hamun says, please, please enjoy the food. It's actually very well-cooked food. My apprentice has been serving me well, perhaps a little bit better on death than he did,
Kostadis Roussos: My, my, my, my, my, my, what is it, my apprentice warden is serving me so much better in death than he served me in life.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Nikhil: Who was he before? Was he your servant as well?
Kostadis Roussos: He told you who he was, his apprentice.
Nikhil: Right, just confirming.
Kostadis Roussos: I hope.
Nikhil: You know, for some reason, I have my suspicions on Hamun. I don't know, it's just, because he's a red wizard or something. I fully don't trust him, but, you know, it's just business.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, so you… you don't trust him, as he's sitting? So tell me, what did you… what did you find? What happened? Did you tell him what happened?
Nikhil: Yeah, so,
Nikhil: The… you know, the party was in a cave, and then we did a… we sneakily attacked
Nikhil: The sentry, and then took out the boss first, and then… The entire party collapsed.
Nikhil: Wow. But there was something strange that we found on one of the cave walls, like.
Nikhil: There was a figure of a goblin, a goblin,
Nikhil: Drawn in charcoal, but there was… You know, crystal-shaped… thing on… on his head.
Nikhil: That was strange to me.
Nikhil: Do you happen to know… Anything about that?
Kostadis Roussos: All of a sudden, his demeanor, which was kind of like, you know… Happy.
Kostadis Roussos: Happy, like, relaxed, suddenly stops.
Kostadis Roussos: You suddenly realize that… why he is a powerful wizard, and he kind of looks at you.
Kostadis Roussos: And his hands sort of fall down like this.
Kostadis Roussos: And he says, I want you to say exactly what you saw.
Kostadis Roussos: Again.
Nikhil: Well… well, Veyra can…
Nikhil: give you the exact details. Where would you like to tell what, you saw on the wall?
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Hamun… Looks at you and says, Fascinating.
Kostadis Roussos: Fascinating.
Kostadis Roussos: Very interesting. And you said, Veyra, you've seen this before.
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Any pauses.
Kostadis Roussos: This is extremely interesting information.
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra.
Kostadis Roussos: And…
Kostadis Roussos: He goes… I don't know what it means.
Kostadis Roussos: You can try rolling your insight to see if you can tell he's lying or not.
Nikhil: Both.
Kostadis Roussos: Here he goes…
Kostadis Roussos: You rolled a 12, right? You can't tell whether he's… you can't tell whether he's telling the truth or not.
Nikhil: Oh, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Hamun looks at you carefully.
Kostadis Roussos: And says.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, it would seem that, my research in this area may actually prove to be very valuable.
Nikhil: I wonder if you… Don't mind, could you explain me in simpler terms?
Nikhil: Is this something we should be worried about?
Kostadis Roussos: So, what do you know about this crystal?
Kostadis Roussos: And these black stones.
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra's about to blurt out everything. Do you let her… do you let her tell her everything?
Nikhil: No, no, actually, no. So…
Nikhil: No, we just, no, we are not aware of those things, but, on the way to Phandalin.
Nikhil: We saw a black crystal somewhere on the way, and then it disappeared.
Kostadis Roussos: Roland Insight Check.
Nikhil: Hmm.
Nikhil: Success.
Kostadis Roussos: You, again, don't notice anything.
Kostadis Roussos: Roll your other allies, roll for your other allies.
Kostadis Roussos: Just roll 3D20, and we'll see what happens.
Nikhil: Almighty God, Master.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: PIP.
Kostadis Roussos: Pip realizes that Hamun knows it… that Hamun shows an… not… like, excitement.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, he's excited when you tell him about the Black Obelisk. Like, he is… this is something he… this is, like, you can see his energy level pumps, just for a moment.
Nikhil: And he hides it again.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, he hides it again.
Nikhil: Okay, alright.
Kostadis Roussos: And he pauses and he says.
Kostadis Roussos: Well, let me say something for you, my dear boy. She looks at Pip. I happen to be an expert archaeologist.
Kostadis Roussos: And in my expertise happens to be the Netheril Empire, and I happen to have more than a passing knowledge of Netheril.
Kostadis Roussos: The language of the ancients.
Kostadis Roussos: And he goes, for example, you see that sword you have?
Nikhil: Yes.
Nikhil: Yes, it's a… What that is… you know…
Nikhil: Made with… forged with diamonds and all the other precious stones.
Kostadis Roussos: It once belonged to a great knight named Aldith Tresendar, known as the Black Hawk.
Nikhil: Tresendar, the names… Seems familiar.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, that Tresendar Manor.
Nikhil: Listen to… no, I'm just, you know, I know, I was gonna…
Nikhil: Yeah, that's one of my dialogues, like…
Kostadis Roussos: is that, like, yeah, okay, I didn't… I thought you were asking me, sorry. That was very, very, very good role-playing. Give yourself a point of inspiration.
Nikhil: Thank you. Tresendar Manor, yes. And Aldith Tresendar, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And so he goes.
Kostadis Roussos: As you can tell, I have made a bit of a habit of learning everything there is to know about this area.
Kostadis Roussos: And, so that's what he kind of, ends.
Kostadis Roussos: So, if you ever find any Netheril artifact, or need any information, just come to Hamun.
Nikhil: Sure, but why was he called the Black Hawk? I have that question. Is it because…
Nikhil: He had any of the black stones or crystals?
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, no, no, no, no, no.
Kostadis Roussos: He was known as the Black Hawk for other reasons.
Kostadis Roussos: Let me just tell you what he was saying.
Kostadis Roussos: He was known as the Black Hawk because he wore black armor and had a habit of wearing a cape.
Nikhil: See, okay, that's interesting.
Kostadis Roussos: And so, it's… the whole idea was that he would show up with his black armor, and the cape would be billowing, and he would be… carry Talon in his hand,
Kostadis Roussos: He pauses.
Nikhil: I was… I just hope,
Nikhil: You know, to keep up to his name when I use this word.
Nikhil: In common.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, well, he goes. That is, he smiles, Hamun goes, yes, Pip, I hope that for you, too.
Kostadis Roussos: And as I said, anything you find related to the Netherese, consider me your expert.
Nikhil: Sure, will do.
Nikhil: I still don't trust Hamun, so I…
Kostadis Roussos: And he turns to Veyra and says, and Veyra, could I take a look at your crystal, if you would be so kind?
Nikhil: No, no, no, we don't tell him that we have the customer.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you didn't tell them about what? You don't tell them about the crystal?
Nikhil: No, no, we just tell him that we came across a crystal on the way here.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, you don't… you don't tell her about Veyra's Blue Crystal.
Nikhil: No, no, no.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, that was my misunderstanding, that's fine. Okay, alright. So, oh yes, and you did tell Veyra to keep her mouth shut.
Nikhil: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right?
Kostadis Roussos: Veyra, you know, has that look that people have who, like, can't keep their mouth shut.
Kostadis Roussos: Like, she wants to… she's about to explode.
Nikhil: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, I don't know whether you've seen, like, the kind of person who walks into a meeting and…
Nikhil: Please.
Kostadis Roussos: It's trying really hard to not say something?
Nikhil: not say something else. I remember, she wanted to talk with the Nothic as well.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so she's got that look of, I've got to ask 100 billion questions right now, right now.
Nikhil: Yeah, I got it,
Kostadis Roussos: But she's… she's, she… you've managed to convince her that maybe this time she should keep her mouth shut.
Kostadis Roussos: And with that, we will end. Before we end, add your… give yourself another level.
Nikhil: Okay.
Nikhil: Manage.
Nikhil: Character, footing…
Nikhil: 114.
Nikhil: Okay… Undated. Yes.
Nikhil: Yes, updated.
Nikhil: This is a new or recently leveled up character sheet beyond Nito.
Kostadis Roussos: Remember to click on the… there's, like, one… you just need to click on one of the things so it can reload the Java.
Nikhil: Right.
Nikhil: Well, like… Refresh.
Nikhil: Page. Reload the page.
Nikhil: Please select the features and traits panel on your DND Beyond character sheet to parse these character features and populate characters, okay?
Kostadis Roussos: If you see… if you see it under… where… where we had the,
Kostadis Roussos: Your spell DC, you click on that, and it'll go away.
Nikhil: Yes, yes, I've updated it. Oh, sorry, not this one.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? So, if you raise your level, I think you gain a feat at 4th level.
Nikhil: You see, the features and traits.
Nikhil: Beautiful.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so, okay, now go to level 4.
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Did you cha- did you adjust your character?
Nikhil: Yeah, when I clicked on the features and traits, the character got adjusted.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, now click on Manage.
Nikhil: Yep, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, now go to Manage Character Levels.
Kostadis Roussos: I scroll up, alright, keep going, scroll down.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so click on this ability score improvement. Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Here's the most annoying part of this game.
Kostadis Roussos: You have the ability to either raise your dexterity.
Kostadis Roussos: Or any of your character ability scores, or pick a feat.
Nikhil: In lots of feet. Oh, like… 100.
Kostadis Roussos: those things. So, I don't have time to… I don't have time now, but if you just go through this.
Nikhil: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: you'll see… there's a lot of different things. I think I gave you the link to,
Kostadis Roussos: I gave you the HTML page. Correct.
Nikhil: Yes, yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: So, go look it over,
Kostadis Roussos: And just pick a feast, alright? So, okay, just to be clear, you can either pick a feast.
Nikhil: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: Or add… or add, 2 ability score points.
Kostadis Roussos: To, like, dexterity or whatever you want.
Nikhil: Alright, so if I select the ability score improvement, I can, you know…
Kostadis Roussos: Bump up your dexterity.
Nikhil: Any of the two scores, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: Yeah, if I choose an athlete, then… I can still…
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so there are two kinds of feats. Feats that give you an ability score improvement and some kind of bonus?
Kostadis Roussos: And some that give you no ability score improvement, but a pretty big bonus. So, for example,
Nikhil: Yeah, like, crossbow does not… You know, just increase my dexterity, but…
Kostadis Roussos: But you can now use it within 5 feet.
Nikhil: Yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right.
Nikhil: Yeah, okay, got it, I'll take a look at this.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so just take a look at this. The other thing is go… get out of here, go to your character sheet, go home, click on home.
Kostadis Roussos: Sorry, I'd rather click on the thing on the… go all the way to the top.
Kostadis Roussos: You see where it has the little next… at the end of what's next?
Nikhil: Sorry.
Nikhil: Yes.
Nikhil: This one.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, go to click on spells.
Kostadis Roussos: Go Manage Spells, that's… Go scroll… click on the… scroll up, scroll down.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, click on Add Spells.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, you can add… you can prepare one more spell.
Nikhil: Hmm, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, so that gives you a fourth spell you can choose from. Again, so look at all of the spells here, and you can pick one.
Nikhil: Got it, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: So, if you scroll down, where it says prepare, like, you can click on one of the prepared ones… prepare ones.
Nikhil: unprepare…
Kostadis Roussos: No, no, why not… you can click on one… you see where it says prepare?
Nikhil: Repair, yes, yes.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so you can click on one of them if you want to do that. Now, spells that have interesting abilities, like, well, you could go read the whole… go read the RPG bot thing.
Nikhil: Yeah.
Kostadis Roussos: But, like, so there's some pretty cool spells, so… and they all have different abilities, right? There's no… some spells are truly epically lame.
Kostadis Roussos: Other ones are not.
Nikhil: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: And some spells are very situational, like, the one time you need it, you're glad you have it.
Kostadis Roussos: The rest of the time, it adds notes.
Nikhil: Okay, okay. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so if you… if you could just do that before our next session, that would be awesome!
Nikhil: Okay, awesome, I'll do that.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: Okay, and if you don't, we'll just do it first thing next session, right?
Nikhil: No, I'll do it, I'll choose.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, so you have the manuals, you can even read the… you can even read it in the manuals if you want.
Nikhil: Okay, okay, cool.
Kostadis Roussos: Right, so I…
Kostadis Roussos: There's probably more spells here than there is in the manual, because I've bought a lot of content, and I've shared it all with you.
Kostadis Roussos: But, like, for some of the spells, you could learn, and some of the basic feats.
Nikhil: Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright.
Nikhil: Yep. Alright, man. Awesome. This was, this was great.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, this was fun. This was fun.
Nikhil: Yep.
Kostadis Roussos: I had, I had fun.
Nikhil: Yeah. Okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Oh, couple things in,
Kostadis Roussos: Charging into a room and killing 5 bug beers is the fastest way to get a third of your party killed.
Nikhil: Okay, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Your party is not built for mass combat.
Nikhil: Okay, I'll keep that in mind, okay.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? You only have… you don't… at the third level, you don't have the ability to attack… to fight a big group of people.
Nikhil: Okay, understood.
Kostadis Roussos: Right? It's only at the fifth level, then, where you can start fighting groups of people.
Nikhil: Understood. When I get promoted, I can take on bigger tasks.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes, yes, so, so just…
Nikhil: Yeah. I'm at an empty S3. Wait to be staffed.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, just, just, I, I, yeah, I just want you to be aware, like, it's not obvious, but…
Nikhil: Well, yeah, yeah, yeah, I understood.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, take care, man.
Nikhil: I don't have to be stupid.
Nikhil: Yeah, got you.
Kostadis Roussos: Yeah, no, and that's why I kind of helped you here, because I'm, like, going… you were acting in a way which showed that you… you were going to get your entire party killed.
Nikhil: Okay, okay. Yeah, yeah, that was a stupid thing.
Kostadis Roussos: It wasn't a stupid thing, you know, you don't understand how the game works, so…
Nikhil: It was a stupid thing to call out all the bugbears out of the cave.
Kostadis Roussos: Yes.
Nikhil: Yeah, yeah, I was thinking something else.
Nikhil: Alright.
Kostadis Roussos: Alright, man. See you closer.
Nikhil: next week.
Kostadis Roussos: Good. Bye.
Nikhil: Bye.